Nicholas D'Angelo Papers
Nicholas D'Angelo Papers
1939-2003
D'Angelo, Nicholas V.
30 linear ft.
Writings, course notes, lectures and scores by the American composer, conductor, musician and teacher.
3945522
Biographical History
Nicholas V. D'Angelo (1929-2010) was a prolific American composer, conductor, musician, and teacher. A veteran of the Korean Conflict, he was a conductor of the United States Air Force Band. Beginning in 1955 and for the next 56 years, he was a professor of music at Hobart and William Smith Colleges in Geneva, New York.
Born in Erie, Pennsylvania December 2, 1929, the son of Polidoro and Josephine D'Angelo, he graduated from the University of Pennsylvania and obtained his master's degree from Syracuse University. He studied under various composition teachers including Bernard Rogers, Luigi Dallapiccola, Paul Hindemith and Earl George, and was a composer-in-residence at La Cite Internationale des Arts in Paris, the University of Redlands in California, Georgia State University, the State University of New York at Oswego and Indiana State University. His many compositions garnered him numerous prizes, honors, and grants, including a 1985 nomination for the Pulitzer Prize in music, Hobart and William Smith Colleges' faculty award for distinguished research and scholarship, first prize at the New American Music Festival, the National Endowment of the Arts, the National Endowment of the Humanities, and numerous commissions, including a notable one from the Society for New Music. His music is recorded on the Roulette, KLP, Century and Spectrum labels.
He and his wife Eva had three children, Paul D'Angelo, Ronald D'Angelo and Barbara Riley. Nicholas D'Angelo died on April 19, 2010 in Penfield, New York at age 80.
(Biographical sketch adapted from obituaries in the Rochester Democrat and Chronicle and the Finger Lakes Times.)
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Nicholas D'Angelo Papers consist of memorabilia, recordings, scores and writings by American composer Nicholas V. D'Angelo and others.
Memorabilia consists primarily of clippings about D'Angelo, his performances and work. There are also nine months' worth of the Hobart Herald (1939-1940), the college newspaper of Hobart and William Smith Colleges, in a bound volume.
Many of the Recordings are of pieces composed by, or performances conducted by, D'Angelo; a few are by others or are unidentified.. Types of music include concertos, chamber music pieces, preludes, string quartet pieces, and more. Many are of live performances, including one by the Ithaca High School Wind Ensemble and one by the Tally-Ho Music Camp Band. Others are of radio broadcasts, such as the James Douthit Simply Grand Concert Broadcast on WVIA-FM. Most are audiorecordings (CDs, 1/4" tapes, and audiocassettes) but there are a few visual items (four film reels and a few VHS cassettes)
Scores are subdivided into those by D'Angelo and those by others, which D'Angelo accumulated for research or teaching purposes. Scores by D'Angelo include symphonies, concertos, sonatas, musical dramas and more. There are pieces for all instruments — brass, woodwind, string, percussion, piano, full orchestra — as well as vocal pieces, such as a Chorale and Alleluia Four-Part Chorus of Mixed Voices. Scores by others include a few by specific composers (Mozart, Debussy, Hindemith, etc.) and a large number of others which D'Angelo had categorized in large folders simply by the instrument for which they were written. These latter are all for brass, percussion or reed instruments.
Writings are also subdivided into those by D'Angelo and those by others. Writings by D'Angelo include his dissertation submitted for the D.Ed. degree, an analysis of a Hindemith madrigale, an essay on the pre-Bach cantata, and more. Writings by others consists of a few typescripts by Diane Stevenson and a report from a Hobart and William Smith Colleges task force.
Arrangement of the Collection
Material is listed below alphabetically by title or topic. In most cases it is also physically arranged that way; however, in many cases there were multiple copies of a score in different sizes, so one piece may be housed in several different boxes depending on size. Writings and Scores are subdivided into those by D'Angelo and those by others.
Related Material
has the papers of a number of composers and musicians, including
Franz Waxman
and
Miklos Rozsa
. In addition, the has an extensive collection of recordings ranging from wax cylinders and early phonodiscs to contemporary commercial recordings.
Separated Material
One published item, a copy of Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart: Complete String Quartets with the Horn and Clarinet Quintets (Dover Study and Playing Editions) has been transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
Subject and Genre Headings
D'Angelo, Nicholas V.; Dallapiccola, Luigi, 1904-1975.; George, Earl, 1924-1994.; Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963.; Rogers, Bernard, 1893-1968.; Hobart and William Smith Colleges.; Society for New Music.; Syracuse University.; University of Pennsylvania.; Chamber music -- 20th century.; Composers -- United States -- 20th century.; Orchestral music -- Scores and parts -- 20th century.; Music -- Manuscripts.; 16mm (photographic film size); Audiocassettes.; Audiotapes.; Compact discs.; Clippings (information artifacts); Educational films.; Film reels.; Manuscripts for publication.; Scores.; Sound recordings.; VHS.; Composers.; Musicians.; Conductors (Music)
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Access to recordings requires advance notice to produce a listening copy.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the estate of Nicholas D'Angelo, 2011.
Additional material, gift of Barbara D'Angelo. 2018.
Inventory
- Memorabilia
  - Miscellaneous, clippings about; program from a performance of D'Angelo music (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous, 1939-1940; undated; includes bound issues of the Hobart Herald (Oversize 17)
- Recordings, Recordings are isted below in alphabetical order based on the title of the piece. Please request by title and ID number. Many of the audiorecordings are of pieces composed and/or performances conducted by D'Angelo; a few are by others and/or are unidentified.
  - Audiorecordings
    - 1980 - NEH Seminar Concert, Oberlin Conservatory [empty box], dangelo_n_065; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 16)
    - 6 Mobiles for Pirandello, dangelo_n_002; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 12)
    - 60th Year Celebration Concert in honor of Nicholas V. D'Angelo, April 23, 1991; dangelo_n_107; The Syracuse Society for New Music and Hobart and William Smith Colleges, Department of Music present a 60th Year Celebration Concert in honor of Nicholas V. D'Angelo, 8:15 PM, Geneva Room, Warren Hunting Smith Library. Accompanied by event's program.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 17)
    - American Dreams, Opaque Images for Viola and Piano, dangelo_n_041; CD (Box 15)
    - Ancient Forms, Functions and Spirit for Flute and Piano, dangelo_n_042; CD (Box 15)
    - Black Music (part 1), dangelo_n_099; Title most likely refers to the National Symposium on Black Music. Reel 1 of 3.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 17)
    - Black Music (part 2), dangelo_n_100; Title most likely refers to the National Symposium on Black Music. Reel 2 of 3.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 17)
    - Black Music (part 3), dangelo_n_101; Title most likely refers to the National Symposium on Black Music. Reel 3 of 3.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 17)
    - Brass Quintet No. 4 (Brass Symposium) [Tape 1], Feb 1971; dangelo_n_003a; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 12)
    - Brass Quintet No. 4 (Brass Symposium) [Tape 2], Feb 1971; dangelo_n_003b; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 12)
    - Capriccio & Improvisations, dangelo_n_043; CD (Box 15)
    - Chamber Music 3 Trios, 12/3/85; dangelo_n_094; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 17)
    - Chamber Music Concert: Compositions of Nicholas D'Angelo, Part I, 13 Nov, 1962; dangelo_n_004; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 12)
    - Chamber Music Concert: Compositions of Nicholas D'Angelo, Part II, 13 Nov, 1962; dangelo_n_005; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 12)
    - Chris Adelmann Demo, dangelo_n_084; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 16)
    - Circolo Bella Artes Concert (radio show in Madrid, Spain), dangelo_n_044; CD, 64 tracks (Box 15)
    - Circolo Bella Artes Concert (radio show in Madrid, Spain), dangelo_n_045; CD, 65 tracks (Box 15)
    - Compositions of Nicholas V. D'Angelo, dangelo_n_006; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 12)
    - Concerto for Orchestra (1972); Brass Quintet No. 4 (1969-70); Divertimento, for Flute, Clarinet, Timpani and Strings (1966-67), 1966-67; 1969-70; 1972; dangelo_n_104; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 17)
    - Concerto for Orchestra (Syracuse Symphony Orchestra), 9 Apr, 1972; dangelo_n_007; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 12)
    - Concerto for Orchestra/Quartet No.3/Seventh Star of Paracelsus, dangelo_n_046; CD (Box 15)
    - Concerto for Orchestra; String Quartet No. 3 (Recorded from Live WONO FM Broadcast); The Seventh Star of Paracelsus for Clarinet, Violin, Cello and Piano by Nicholas V. D'Angelo [empty box], 1968; 1972; 1974; dangelo_n_103; Label on the box reads: "Prof. Nicholas V. D'Angelo, Chairman, Department of Music, Hobart and William Smith Colleges, Geneva, New York 14456".; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 17)
    - Divertimento for Flute, Clarinet, Timpani, and Strings, dangelo_n_008; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 12)
    - Echoes Six Band (Schola and Band) (2), dangelo_n_097; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 17)
    - Eleventh Annual Symposium of American Music, 26-27 Mar 1966; dangelo_n_009; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 12)
    - Fall Concert 1969 Presents Symphonic Wind Ensemble, Nicholas V. D'Angelo, Conductor, dangelo_n_093; Event's program is inside the tape box.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 16)
      Side 1: Amparito Roca (Spanish March), J. Texidor; Tone Poem For Band "A Prayer to Young Man Died in Winter Mountain", S. Iwakawa; Trumpets of Splendor (Concert March), J. Cacavas; My Fair Lady (Symphonic Scenario), F. Loewe and A. Lerner, arr. J. Cacavas; Pavane for Dead Princess, M. Ravel; Side 2: Finale for Symphony No. 5, D. Shostakovich
    - Fall Wind Festival Present the Colleges-Community Concert Band, Nicholas V. D'Angelo, Conductor (2 of X), 29 Nov. 1966; dangelo_n_092; Bristol Gymnasium. Reel No. 2. Event's program is inside the tape box and handwritten notes are on the box.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 16)
    - A Flight in the Blue: Opening - Lift Your Head (March); Mano del Morta (Hand of Death) (orch.); Shangrila (Symphonic Wind Ensemble), dangelo_n_010; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 12)
    - Hobart and William Smith Jazz Band, Hastie's Jazz Club, March 14, 1986; dangelo_n_067; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 16)
    - Hobart and William Smith Jazz Ensemble, Hastie's Jazz Club, Greenock [empty box], November 14, 1986; dangelo_n_068; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 16)
    - Illinois Wesleyan University Collegiate Choir and University Choir, Dr. Nott and Dr. Kuam, Director, Fall 1989; dangelo_n_069; Westbrook Auditorium. Recorded by Drew Duquette. Accompanied by Illegible old label.; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 16)
    - James Douthit Simply Grand Concert Broadcast on WVIA-FM, 25 May, 2003; dangelo_n_047; CD (Box 15)
    - Jazz lab Ensemble Concert at St. John The Divine Cathedral, 5/5/79; dangelo_n_064; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 16)
    - Kandinsky Variations, dangelo_n_082; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 16)
    - Kandinsky Variations for Piano, dangelo_n_048; CD (Box 15)
    - La Cité International des Arts, 14 Mar, 1967; dangelo_n_011; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 12)
    - Las Vegas - Carl Fontana; Bill Watrous, dangelo_n_077; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 16)
      Side A: 2 Trombones - NPR; Side B: Dave King - WRVO; Ray [?]
    - Load the Busses - Concert March (Played by the Tally-Ho Music Camp Band), 8 Aug, 1963; dangelo_n_012; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 12)
    - Load the Buses/National Guardian/Crown Pointe March, dangelo_n_049; CD (Box 15)
    - Masks of Innocence Other Enchantments, dangelo_n_050; CD (Box 15)
    - My Fair Lady, Original Broadway Cast (part 1 and 2), dangelo_n_081; "My Fair Lady" is a musical based George Bernard Shaw's "Pygmalion" with lyrics by Alan Jay Lerner and music by Frederick Loewe. This recording is Original Broadway Cast (part 1 and 2), starring Rex Harrison, Julie Andrews, Stanley Holloway and Robert Coote.; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Box 16)
      Side A: "Overture"; "Why Can't The English?"; "Wouldn't It be Loverly"; "With a Little Bit of Luck"; "I'm an Ordinary Man"; "Just You Wait"; "The Rain in Spain"; "I Could Have Danced All Night"; Side B: "Ascot Gavotte"; "On the Street Where You Live"; "You Did It"; "Show Me"; "Get Me to the Church on Time"; "A Hymn to Him"; "Without You"; "I've Grown Accustomed to Her Face"
    - Nick V. D'Angelo in Concert with the Colleges Community Symphonic Wind Orchestra, November 9, 1989; dangelo_n_095; Winn-Sealy Gym. Accompanied by event's program.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 17)
    - No Sad Songs for Julie, dangelo_n_013; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 12)
    - No Sad Songs for Julie, 1971; dangelo_n_014; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 13)
    - No Sad Songs for Julie, dangelo_n_051; CD (Box 15)
    - No Sad Songs for Julie (Premier Performance by the Ithaca High School Wind Ensemble), 10 May, 1973; dangelo_n_015; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 13)
    - No Sad Songs for Julie [performed by] United States Air Force Band, dangelo_n_016; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 13)
    - NTSU Jazz Guitar Ensemble, 1982; dangelo_n_066; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 16)
      Start with Mrs. Beanhart - Rob McConnell; March of the Tadpoles - Toshiko A.; Easy to Love - S. guitars, arr. Young, based on Cannonball, Adderly solo; Bundle O'Funk - Nestico
    - Ode, dangelo_n_017; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 13)
    - Ode, 1965; dangelo_n_018; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 13)
    - Ode and Concerto, dangelo_n_019; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 13)
    - Ode of Dedication, 16 Oct, 1965; dangelo_n_020; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 13)
    - Of Voices and Winds (3), dangelo_n_098; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 17)
    - Orchestration, dangelo_n_078; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 16)
    - Part I - "In Memoriam" by Lindsay Lafford; Part II - Part 1 of the Mozart Requiem, 20 Mar, 1956; dangelo_n_001; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 12)
    - Prelude in A Minor - Chorale and March, dangelo_n_021; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 13)
    - Psalms Triptych, dangelo_n_022; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 13)
    - Recorded Examples from the Text and Workbook "Composing For the Jazz Orchestra" by William Russo and Reid Hyams, 1979; dangelo_n_085; conducted by William Russo and Joseph Reiser, narrated by Reid Hyams. More detailed information about the content and performers is printed on the cover.; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 61:27 (Box 16)
    - Reel No. 1, 22 Oct, 1966; dangelo_n_023; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 13)
    - Regional Composers Concert (Society for New Music Concert), 2-sided, dangelo_n_024; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 13)
    - Seventh Star of Paracelsus, dangelo_n_052; CD (Box 13)
    - Seventh Star of Paracelsus (Hamilton College Chapel), 29 Sep, 1979; dangelo_n_025; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 13)
    - Show Boat, dangelo_n_083; Show Boat is a musical in two acts with music by Jerome Kern and lyrics by Oscar Hammerstein II, based on Edna Ferber's novel "Show Boat".; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 16)
    - Society for New Music Concert, 28 Sep, 1988; dangelo_n_026; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 13)
    - Some Summer Sun, dangelo_n_053; CD (Box 15)
    - Sonatina for Violin and Orchestra (Festival of the Arts, Victor Central School) May 1964, dangelo_n_027; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 13)
    - Sonoria No. 1, 1976; dangelo_n_028; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 14)
    - Sonoria No. 1 for Tenor solo, S. A. T. B. chorus, Clarinet and Piano, N. V. D'Angelo, dangelo_n_074; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Box 16)
    - Sonoria No. 1, N. V. D'Angelo, dangelo_n_073; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Box 16)
    - Spring Concert / The William Smith Singers and The Jazz-Lab Ensemble, 18 May, 1977; dangelo_n_029; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 14)
    - Spring Pops Concert, 3 May, 1966; dangelo_n_030; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 14)
    - String Quartet, dangelo_n_031; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 14)
    - String Quartet No. 3 (Manhattan String Quartet), dangelo_n_032; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 14)
    - String Quartet No. 3, dangelo_n_054; CD (Box 15)
    - String Quartet No. 6 in two movements, Nicholas V. D'Angelo, dangelo_n_075; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 45:00 (Box 16)
    - String Quartet No. 6, dangelo_n_055; CD (Box 15)
    - String Quartet No. 7, dangelo_n_056; CD (Box 15)
    - A Student Recital, February 28, 1991; dangelo_n_106; Department of Music, Hobart and William Smith Colleges present A Student Recital, February 28, 1991, 8:00 PM at Geneva Room Warren Hunting Smith Library. Accompanied by event's program.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 17)
      Side 1: Prelude and Fugue in Bb major, BWV 866, from Das wohltemperirte Clavier, I, J. S. Bach; Intermezzo in A major, Op. 118, No. 2, Johannes Brahms; Sonate: Massig bewegt, Paul Hindemith; Concerto, No. 2, k. 314: Andante ma non troppo, Allegro aperto, W. A. Mozart; Side 2: Sechs Kleine Praludien, BWV 933: No. 1, C. major; No. 4, major; No. 6, E minor, J. S. Bach; Sonata, K. 309, Allegro con spirito, W. A. Mozart
    - Sundays of Note - The Amani Singers Gospel Choir, 2/21/93; dangelo_n_072; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 16)
    - Sundays of Note - Syracuse Society for New Music (Copy), 2/14/93; dangelo_n_071; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 16)
    - Sundays of Note - Syracuse Society for New Music (Original), 2/14/93; dangelo_n_070; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 16)
    - Symphony No. 3 (An Ode of Dedication), 1965-1966; dangelo_n_033; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 14)
    - Symphony No. 3 (An Ode of Dedication) (Bristol Gym, Hobart & William Smith Colleges), 1 May, 1972; dangelo_n_034; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 14)
    - Symphony No. 3 (An Ode of Dedication) for S. A. T. B. Solo Voices, S. A. T. B. Chorus, Organ, Harpsichord and Orchestra by Nicholas V. D'Angelo, dangelo_n_105; A Choral Symphony on text selected from Leaves of Grass by Walt Whitman. Label on the box reads: "Prof. Nicholas V. D'Angelo, Chairman, Department of Music, Hobart and William Smith Colleges, Geneva, New York 14456".; 1/4 inch audio tape; running time 30:00 (Box 17)
    - Symphony No. 3 by N. V. D'Angelo, May, 1972; dangelo_n_076; Choral Symphony, An Ode of Dedication for S. A. T. B. solos, S. A. T. B. chorus, Organ, Harpsichord and Orchestra. Hobart and William Smith Festival Chorus, Syracuse Symphony Orchestra, Nicholas V. D'Angelo, Conducting; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 30:00 (Box 16)
    - Syracuse Society for New Music Concert, 13 Mar, 1984; dangelo_n_035; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 14)
    - Tape 1 performed 28 Oct 1960; recorded 16 Nov 1960, dangelo_n_036; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 14)
    - Time for Change, dangelo_n_058; CD, 28 tracks (Box 15)
    - Time for Change, dangelo_n_057, 4 tracks; CD (Box 15)
    - Time Passages for Piano, dangelo_n_059; CD, 1 track (Box 15)
    - Time Passages for Piano, dangelo_n_060; CD, 2 tracks (Box 15)
    - Trio Violin, Cello & Piano, dangelo_n_061; CD (Box 15)
    - Types of Show Songs, dangelo_n_079; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Box 16)
    - Types of Show Songs: Charm Songs; Overtures, dangelo_n_080; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 16)
    - Various Actions for Wind Quintet, 16 Mar, 1982; dangelo_n_037; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 15)
    - Various Actions for Wind Quintet, dangelo_n_062; CD (Box 15)
    - Voice of America, 1966; dangelo_n_038; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 14)
    - W. Nichols - Sve. Ann Steck (M. Chalker), dangelo_n_040; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 14)
    - Wind Quintet No. 2, 4 tracks, dangelo_n_063; CD (Box 15)
    - WONO Live Broadcast, dangelo_n_102; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 17)
    - Woodwind Quintet No. 2, 1963; dangelo_n_039; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 14)
    - [Untitled], dangelo_n_086; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 30:00 (Box 16)
    - [Untitled], dangelo_n_087; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 16)
    - [Untitled], dangelo_n_096; handwritten note inserted in the box, illegible; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 17)
  - Film and video
    - Folk Music in the Concert Hall (part 1), dangelo_n_110; educational film featuring folk music performed at Carnegie Hall. Part 1 of 2. Accompanied by old film label, stamped by the Department of Music, Hobart and William Smith Colleges, Geneva, New York.; Film: 16mm ([barcoded item])
    - Folk Music in the Concert Hall (part 2), 1961; dangelo_n_111; educational film featuring folk music performed at Carnegie Hall. Part 2 of 2.; Film: 16mm ([barcoded item])
    - Jazz in the Concert Hall (part 1), dangelo_n_108; educational film featuring jazz and fusion during concerts. Part 1 of 2. Accompanied by film guide.; Film: 16mm; running time 32:00 ([barcoded item])
    - Jazz in the Concert Hall (part 2), 1964; dangelo_n_109; educational film featuring jazz and fusion during concerts. Part 2 of 2. Accompanied by film guide.; Film: 16mm; running time 25:00 ([barcoded item])
    - [Untitled], dangelo_n_088; VHS; running time 60:00 (Box 16)
    - Sundays of Note, 3/7/93; dangelo_n_089; VHS; running time 120:00 (Box 16)
    - Sundays of Note, 3/7/93; dangelo_n_090; VHS; running time 120:00 (Box 16)
    - Sundays of Note - The Amani Gospel Choir, 2/21/93; dangelo_n_091; VHS; running time 30:00 (Box 16)
- Scores
  - By D'Angelo
    - 3 Miniatures for Wind Ensemble (Box 1)
    - 3 Miniatures for Wind Ensemble, oversize score (Oversize 1)
    - 9 Petite Figures for Flute, B-flat Clarinet and Bassoon (Oversize 1)
    - American Dreams, Opaque Images for Viola and Piano (Box 1)
    - American Dreams, Opaque Images for Viola and Piano, oversize score (Oversize 1)
    - Among Other Voices…of Love for Wind Ensemble (Box 1)
    - Among Other Voices…of Love for Wind Ensemble, oversize score, parts (Oversize 1)
    - An Ode of Dedication for Solo Voices, Chorus, Organ, Harpsichord and Orchestra (Box 1)
    - Ancient Forms, Functions and Spirit for Flute and Piano (Box 1)
    - Ancient Forms, Functions and Spirit for Flute and Piano, oversize score (Oversize 2)
    - Ancient Forms, Functions and Spirit No. 2 for Flute and Piano (Box 1)
    - Ancient Forms, Functions and Spirit No. 2 for Flute and Piano, oversize score, proofs (Oversize 16)
    - Bagatelles and Tangos for Piano (Box 1)
    - Beyond the Other I (duo concertante) for Violin & Violoncello (Box 1)
    - Beyond the Other I (duo concertante) for Violin & Violoncello, oversize score (Oversize 2)
    - Brass Quintet No. 3 (Box 1)
    - Brass Quintet No. 3, oversize score (Oversize 2)
    - Brass Quintet No. 4 (Box 1)
    - Brass Quintet No. 4, oversize score (Oversize 2)
    - Bridges of Time for Wind Quintet (Box 1)
    - Bridges of Time for Wind Quintet, oversize score, parts (Oversize 2)
    - Capriccio and Improvisations for Alto Saxophone and Chamber Orchestra, oversize score, parts (Oversize 2)
    - Capriccio and Improvisations for Alto Saxophone and Symphonic Band, oversize score (Oversize 2)
    - Cask of Amontillado (an Opera in One Act) (Box 1)
      See also Writings: By D'Angelo: Cask of Amontillado (lyrics)
    - Celestial Three for Symphonic Band and Speaker (optional) (Box 2)
    - Celestial Three for Symphonic Band and Speaker (optional), oversize score (Oversize 3)